[Music]
Welcome to expert says the official
podcast series of Rahan Mandri Fazalvi
Mayojna where we bring you insights from
leaders innovators and experts who are
shaping the future of agriculture
insurance in India. In this episode, we
are honored to be joined by Shri Anandan
Singhi, chief retail and government
business at ICI Lombard General
Insurance. Tune in as we explore the
evolving role of technology,
collaboration and innovation in
delivering timing, transparent and
efficient crop insurance under PMFY.
Welcome to our podcast expertise. Today
we have Mr. Anan Singhi joining us.
Welcome to our podcast sir. Thank you.
as uh one of the biggest insurance
company ICICA Lombard and uh as one of
the most important stakeholder how do
you see the evolvement of uh PMBBY over
the past few years. So you first of all
we should be very very proud uh to the
fact that we represent being part of the
world's largest crop insurance scheme
which is
praan scheme in terms of the number of
farmers enrolled and it's the world's
third largest scheme in terms of the
premiums which which are done under the
scheme right and I can go back to year
2016 when all of this started right and
in that particular year when it was at a
concept stage and when it got fractified
into execution
This game was all about manual model,
right? So we had manual enrollment,
manual claims going uh reaching across
in all sort of activities in a fairly uh
kind of unstructured manner given the
fact that we were setting this game. But
if you would talk about how we have
moved ahead and how we have come so far
and this being the 10th year of
exhibition of the PMBB scheme. I think
the fundamental change which has
happened in the scheme is that we've
been able to migrate away from a manual
construct to a tech first construct. And
I'll try to illustrate or elaborate more
on why do I say about this. Uh if you
look across with the value chain there
are three or four very critical stages
in good execution of a crop insurance
scheme. So first we begin with
enrollment process right. So at a point
in time where everything was manual
people were using spreadsheets to just
data enter the list of the farmers which
were insured to a point today where
everything is automated in the NCIP
portal. Yeah. And then there are portals
which have been designed which are
significantly also helping the partners
ecosystem to be able to enroll more and
more farmers in this particular cause.
Right? So there's a significant
operating change from being manual
intensive to tech first again in terms
of enrollment. If I move next and when
we talk about claims, so there was a
point in time where obviously after the
manual crop cutting experiments were
completed, the entire exercise of
compilation of results again used to be
fairly in spreadsheets and there were
layers through which the information
used to cross eventually to come to a
point where payments could be made and
as we speak today we know that there is
the DG claims portal which facil
facilitates auto transfer of payments to
the beneficiary's account. I think
that's a big thumbs up big plus which
has happened which has allowed farmers
to kind of really genuinely believe that
the scheme is helping them in a sign
significant way. Also to touch on a
critical point uh crop insurance claims
were always dependent on manual CC
results and there was always questions
about uh credibility of the value which
was getting computed. There was always
two and fros happening to a point where
where the government now today
thankfully has developed technologies
like yes which allows crop payment to
happen basis yield computation which are
tech based and there are whole host of
states in different proportion who are
using this automated technology of yield
assessment I think that's again uh gets
ratified into the techfaced approach and
last not the least if we talk about from
an execution and a grievance handling
perspective because that's the voice of
farmers which you have to hear across
multiple insurance companies, multiple
call centers, multi multiple physical
data points and today as we speak we
have a fully automated one-stop call
center solution right which is in terms
of krishi ruak solution which is
available for the farmers to kind of
intimate their claims or kind of really
have their grievances put across. So in
summary, Isha, if you were to really see
through from a phenomenal intensive
model, operating intensive model which
was all completely manual to a scenario
to a to a point today where where most
of the things are tech first and the
government is continuing to build new
and new solutions on on technology first
approach. I think this has been the core
foundation change which has happened in
the crop insurance scheme. As a
resulting factor, if you look across
from a point in time few years back
where we had less than three core
farmers being insured to a point in the
last financial year where we have put
those six core farmers being insured. I
think doubling the enrollments is again
a big achievement which has happened in
this scheme. We all we are already
talking that yes there are the number of
farmers which are insured are still less
than 40%. And how do we get to 100%
insurance? In my opinion, the way the
PMA scheme is being implemented by the
central and the state governments, we
are not far away where we are going to
see 100% of the farmers being enrolled
in the cop insurance scheme. That's a
wonderful insight on the evolution of
PMB by throughout all these years. What
are the some key innovation and
strategies uh does these insurance
company has brought in the
implementation of PMF in last few years?
So I think um a part of this response
will be fairly in line with what I spoke
earlier right. So and we have to really
go back in time when crop insurance
started and when it started a whole host
of private insurance company started to
participate in the crop insurance
scheme. Yeah. And as being part of
private insurance company we realized
that if you continue to operate on
manual operating model it will be very
very difficult to scale the scheme and
scale the scheme in a way in which it
could kind of make sense across the
ecosystem. as uh part of private
insurance setup. What we started to do
at that point in time was to kind of
possibly house grow these tech based
systems at our end individually. So for
an example a private insurance company
would have developed its own mobile app
for claim computation and claim
assessment and similarly many more
companies would have been doing that.
The government realized that there was
benefit in kind of consolidating all
these initiatives under one roof and try
to see that okay how the technology
could be a common technology which could
be used for all the players rather than
individual technological solutions which
each company would have brought across.
So in my opinion in the operating
framework the private insurance
companies played a very very significant
role and eventually the collaborative
effort between the private insurance
companies as well as the government of
India and the state governments led to
today a point where most of the
solutions are centrally available for
all stakeholders. This apart uh some of
the areas where as private insurance we
also played a critical role was to kind
of also understand the risk management
management element really well. So
historically I mean the entire process
at point in time used to work where
there were enrollment and there were
final claims but we were forgetting a
very critical missing element which was
the crop health monitoring and
understanding the risk of the crop at
different stages of its growth cycle.
That's another area where where as
private insurance we significantly
started to invest understand what was
happening on patents understand what is
the communication which was required to
be made to the farmers on a consistent
basis curate and construct campaigns
around it right and again that was an
area which got picked up by the central
government and a whole host of
initiatives now again are centrally run
around that. So similarly across various
uh stages right in the life cycle of the
crop cycle at every stage we realized
that there were merit to kind of
initiate a few set of activities and we
consulted and collaborated with the
government in a significant way to be
able to address all those challenges
which were kind of existing for us and
we continue to do that. So crop
insurance again is very very close to
lot of us and we go all out to ensure
that the real set of operating model can
be designed so as to ensure that on a
tech first approach we can exude crop
insurance in a large way. That's great
to know so many changes happen in crop
insurance through insurance companies.
Mr. Singing what does your team does to
make sure that there is a transparency
and accountability especially with while
working with some government schemes
like PMFY.
So is again uh good question in fact a
very very good question that how do we
ensure that given the fact that this
scheme entails a lot of servicing to our
farmers right who are the real backbone
of the economy how do we ensure that we
are implementing this scheme in the true
set of spirit. So what we did at our end
was we created a very strong operating
framework and created governance
councils around that which used to kind
of monitor each of the activities which
was should to be done in crop insurance
in a fairly detailed manner. To begin
with it started with data governance and
data committees where we started to
absorb lot of data before we were even
quoting for the tenders which are
opening up for crop insurance. from
there to also ensuring that we had the
best of the-class teams being recruited
on the ground being skilled enough so
that the necessary conversation and
communication between the teams and the
farmers as well as the state and central
governments was absolutely in line. Uh
we ensured that communication protocols
were very very strongly established
there. There were protocols which were
established in terms of how you would
communicate back to the ground. How will
you communicate with the government?
What are the quality of the reports
which you'll have to kind of submit time
and again which internally meant that
there there had to be a significant
cadence right of kind of really ensuring
that the core elements which are
required to be executed well were being
executed well. Internally in our
organization also we have a we have a
framework through which we at the senior
most level in the in the organization
would also review all the critical
activities which are to be done in the
most uh proper manner to implement the
crop insurance scheme in a in in the in
the right way and we are I think we all
just kind of go about putting our
efforts to see that every single step
which is required to be done the right
way is done in the right way. It's so
great to know that your team is so
responsible for all the accountability
and transparency. Mr. Sing what step
should the industry take so that uh
current uh percentage of 30% enrollment
of our farmers increase and we reach our
target of 100% enrollment of all the
farmers. So again Isaiah your questions
are absolutely spot on like always right
and I must tell that the I mean there is
a larger macro theme which is going in
our country which is to ensure that
towards Vix we have insurance for all by
2047. Yeah. And to do that the most
important element which will be required
is to see that crop insurance scheme
penetrates at 100% level. Now how do we
really go about it right? So if you
again go back in time or or kind of see
the recent set of feedback which we have
been getting from most of the people on
the ground uh there's a there's a
requirement of ensuring that the claim
process needs to be completely
reimagined. Yeah. As we speak today,
there is a significant considerable
amount of delay which happens between
the claim computation and the claim
payment given the fact that the the
scheme of subsidy between the state and
the central government and eventual
realization by the insurance company has
got some bit of time lag. There is very
active conversation which is happening
between the governments and the
insurance companies to figure out what
is the right operating model to ensure
that the claim payments can be made at a
significant fast pace because if we are
not able to make the payment when the
farmer actually needs it I think it's
too late in the day there. So in my view
one of the most important element which
we have to do is we have to completely
reimagine the claims journey which we
today have. Uh alongside it there's a
significant requirement to build huge
amount of capability as well as capacity
in the entire ecosystem. So which which
essentially means that we have to
recruit more people. We have to do
enough and more amount awareness
campaigns. We have to make sure that the
operating processes are designed in a
way in which every farmer understands
the benefit of crop insurance and most
importantly after that I think the
insurance and the reinsurance will have
to put significant amount of capital
towards kind of building this business
in a in a right uh right right possible
manner. So in my opinion if we can
reimagine the claim journey if you can
invest on consumer or farmer awareness
and we can kind of really stitch the
operating model in a way which kind of
really has farmer first when it in its
entire thought process or farmer at the
center when it's kind of really building
out all the journeys. I think these are
some of the small small steps which
you'll have to take to be able to reach
to our ultimate goal of ensuring that
each and every farmer in our country is
completely insured. Mr. Those were some
very key and valuable inputs and we
would like to thank you for joining us
today on our podcast expert. Thank you
so much. Lovely experience. It was an
absolute pleasure. Thank you so much.
Thank you sir.
[Music]